Guide to the Sterling Memorial Library, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Sterling Memorial Library, Yale University, photographs
1927-2003
RU 696
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.02
(17 boxes)
The materials consist of photographs and pictures of Sterling Memorial Library at Yale. Includes views of interiors, exteriors, decoration, and construction.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in three series and subsequent accessions. I. Construction Progress Photographs, 1927-1930. II. Interiors, Exteriors, and Decoration, circa 1927-1969. III. Negatives, circa 1930s-1940.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs and pictures of Sterling Memorial Library at Yale. Includes views of interiors, exteriors, decoration, and construction.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Academic libraries; College buildings; Negatives (photographs); Photographs; Slides (photographs); Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University. Library
- Construction progress photos, 1927-1930; Series I
  - Excavation, 1927 October - November (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Construction
    - 1928 January-February (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1928 March-April (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1928 May-June (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1928 July-August (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1928 September-October (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1928 November-December (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1929 January-February (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1929 March-April (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1929 May-June (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1929 July-August (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1929 September-October (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1929 November-December (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1930 January-February (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1930 March-April (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1930 May-June (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Presentation Ceremony, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous views (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Construction workers, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 127-128)
- Interiors, exteriors, and decoration, circa 1927-1960s; Series II
  - Library site, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Construction, general
    - 1927 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Stack tower, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
    - 1929 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1930 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mezzanine construction, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Exterior views
    - High Street entrance, 1930 - circa 1932 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - High Street entrance, late, 1930s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - From Cross Campus, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - From Cross Campus (negatives only), 1940s (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - From Cross Campus, 1950s, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
    - From Cross Campus, drawings (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Entrance, Librarian's Office, from court (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Entrance, Wall Street (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Entrance York Street (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Service entrance to shipping, Wall Street (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Corner of High and Wall Streets (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Librarian's Court (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Librarian's Court, detail: fountain (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Light Court (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Stack Tower, from Librarian's Court, circa 1930 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Stack Tower, from York Street (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Stack Tower, facing Elm Street, 1930-1932 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Interior views
    - Nave (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Nave (drawings) (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Nave, detail: window, card catalogue (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Nave, detail: exhibition cases (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Circulation desk (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Circulation desk, detail: Savage mural (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Crossing, towards Main Reading Room (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Crossing, towards Cloister (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Crossing, detail: screen and arch to Cloister (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Cloister Exhibition Corridor (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Exhibition Hall (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Exhibition cases (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Linonia and Brothers Reading Room (Box 4, Folder 41-42)
    - Main Reading Room to North End (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Main Reading Room to South End (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Main Reading Room, details (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Periodicals Wing, drawing (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Periodical Reading Room (Reserve Book Room) (Box 4, Folder 47-49)
    - Manuscripts and Archives (Rare Book Room), 1930-1963 (Box 4, Folder 50-51)
    - Manuscripts and Archives reading room, details: exhibition cases (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Manuscripts and Archives, detail: alcove (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Manuscripts and Archives, detail: arch to Gutenburg Room (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Microtext Reading Room (Periodicals Room until ca. 1970) (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - 1742 Library (Box 5, Folder 56-57)
    - 1742 Library, detail: books, doors (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Work areas (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Elevators to stacks (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Personnel office (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - University Librarian's office (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Room 226, Historical Sound Recordings (Speck-German Collection) (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Room 406, Slavic Reading Room (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Room 232 Benjamin Franklin Collection (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Magazine Collection, Rooms 707-710 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Asia Reading Room, Room 219 (American Lit. Collection) (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Andrew's Study--History Room, Room 214-215 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Basement, Government Documents/Microtext (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Basement, Bibliography Room (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Basement, Archives vault (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Arts of the Book Room, Room 177 (Memorabilia) (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Stacks (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Decoration
    - [J. G. Rogers'] Scrapbooks for ideas, volume 1 (Box 6, Folder 74-75)
    - [J. G. Rogers'] Scrapbooks for ideas, volume 2 (Box 7, Folder 76-77)
    - Models for stone carving
      - Bosses (Box 8, Folder 78-80)
      - Corbels (Box 8, Folder 81-82)
      - Niches (Box 8, Folder 83-85)
      - Capitals (Box 8, Folder 86-87)
      - Arches to Cloister (Box 8, Folder 88)
      - Moldings: scene panels, label stops, etc. (Box 8, Folder 89-92)
      - Figured reliefs (Box 8, Folder 93-94)
      - Entrance, portals, facade (Box 9, Folder 95)
      - Shields, arms (Box 9, Folder 96)
      - Allegorical relief statues (Box 9, Folder 97)
      - Friezes (Box 9, Folder 98)
      - Inscriptions (Box 9, Folder 99)
      - Rooftop sculptures and gargoyles (Box 9, Folder 100-101)
      - Librarian's Court, L and B windows, carvings (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - Commemorative reliefs (Nave)
      - "Pledging the Books--1701" (Box 9, Folder 103)
      - "Jeremiah Drummer's gift of books--1714" (Box 9, Folder 104)
      - "Demanding Books in Saybrook--1718" (Box 9, Folder 105)
      - "First Commencement in New Haven--1718" (Box 9, Folder 106)
      - "Bishop Berkeley's Gift--1732" (Box 9, Folder 107)
      - "The First Catalogue by President Clap--1742" (Box 9, Folder 108)
      - "Founding of Linonia Society--1753" (Box 9, Folder 109)
      - "Founding of Brothers in Unity--1768" (Box 9, Folder 110)
      - "British invasion of New Haven--1779" (Box 9, Folder 111)
      - "Resignation of Librarian Daniel Coit Gillman--1865" (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - Commemorative relief (rejected) (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - "Commencement in New Haven--1718" (Box 9)
      - Window paintings (Box 9, Folder 114-116)
      - Schwab Fountain, High Street exterior (Box 9, Folder 117)
      - Ironwork, negatives only (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Decoration, general (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Decoration, miscellaneous: contact sheets (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Architectural details and drawings (photographs of)
    - Detail, Yellin gate, Manuscripts and Archives (Box 9, Folder 121)
    - Detail, upper part of fireplace (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - Proposal drawings (Box 9, Folder 123)
    - Rejected plans (Rogers) (Box 9, Folder 124)
    - Architect's drawings and elevations (Box 9, Folder 125)
    - Floor plans (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - Oversize
    - Exterior views (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Interior views (Box 12, Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 1742 room (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Proposed Renovations and Construction, 1960's (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
    - Drawing of stained glass window, Exhibit Corridor medallion replacement EC-1, by Frederick Cole, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Slides (Box 13)
  - Transparencies
    - Exterior (Box 14)
    - Linonia Brothers Library (Box 14)
    - High Street entrance (Box 14)
- Negatives, circa 1930s-1940; Series III
  - Bibliographic Press (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Decoration
    - Bosses and Corbels (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Cornices (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Exhibit Hall (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Fountain (Librarian's Court) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Manuscripts and Archives (Rare Book Room) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Model #88--"Removing the books..." (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Nave (glass plate negatives) (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Penniman Room, window: "Hopkins Grammar School" (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - View of High Street facade--James Gamble Rogers (drawing) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - High Street entrance, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Photographs of the Franke Family Reading Room in Sterling Memorial Library, Circa 2003; Accession 2006-A-044; 0.25; (1 box) (Box 1)
- Photographs used in Nota Bene, 1990-1991; Accession 2011-A-006
  Scope and Contents
  Photographs taken by Michael Marsland, Yale University Office of Public Information.
  - Music Library buttress construction, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Two Philosophers Discussing the Cosmos, Maffei, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Entrance porch details: stone webs; bosses; sea monsters, ship, compass; iron grilles in front of radiators by Samuel Yellin, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ceiling and woodwork details, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Windows: Japanese warriors and dancers, 1990
  - International Law Library, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Isaach Newton buttress, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Peru and South America map stained window, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coronation book of Tsar Nicholas II, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - CD-ROM reference center, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Recent acquisitions of Arabic and Islamic Reading Room, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stained glass windows, woodwork, and special collection material, crica 1989 (Box 2)
- Photographs of stonework removed from exterior of Sterling Memorial Library, 2018; Accession 2018-A-0077
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Exterior stonework removed from Sterling Memorial Library, 2018
    Restricted in-process